

Sugandha Katoch Industrial Design Centre Indian Institute of Technology, Bombay

Specialization: Interaction Design

196330006 M.Des.

Gender: Female DOB: 13-12-1994

Examination	University	Institute	Year	CPI / %
Post Graduation	IIT Bombay	IIT Bombay	2021	7.88
Graduation	NMIMS	Mukesh Patel School of Technology	2016	75.75%
		Management and Engineering		
Graduation Specialization	zation: Computer Engineering			

Profile

If I had to describe myself in one word, I would choose the adjective - 'curious'. With an interest in emerging technologies, I like to explore designerly ways of thinking, and apply service design methodologies to my design process in order to create meaningful experiences.

Education

IDC School of Design, IIT Bombay June '21 M. Des. Interaction Design

MPSTME, NMIMS University June '16 B. Tech. in Computer Engineering

R. N. Podar School, CBSE Mumbai June '12 12th – [76% Percentage] 10th – [10/10 CGPA]

Skills

User experience

Contexual Inquiries, User Research, Personas, Storyboarding, Usability Testing

Visualisation

Concept Sketching, Wireframing, Rapid prototyping, Data visualisation, Creative Coding

Programming

HTML, CSS, JavaScript, Processing, UNIX, C#

Software

Figma, InVision, Adobe Suite [Adobe XD, InDesign, Illustrator, Photoshop, Premiere Pro], Blender, Lens Studio

Publication

Co-authored in a paper named "How real is virtual reality - An immersion, interaction and embodiedness study" at ICoRD '21.

Portfolio

https://sugandha-katoch.github.io/

Work Experience

IDC School of Design, IIT Bombay Jul 2019 - Present

ACM SIGCHI Student Chapter, IIT Bombay [Member]; PG Sports Dept. head [Female]; Sustainability Cell [Volunteer].

Palpx Apr 2020 – Jul 2020

UX research for the Generative Design, with an aim to bridge the gap and enhance the design decisions taken by machines.

Accenture Nov 2016 – May 2018

Worked on Siebel (CRM) admin operations for a telecom giant based in UK. Designed dashboards to visualise and display important application server health status parameters. Assisted various stakeholders during a major project transition.

Pawan Hans LTD Jul 2014 – Aug 2014

Researched, developed and presented an information architecture model for an Employee Leave Management System for the company, while working under its IT dept.

Youth Online Learning Organisation Sep 2020 – Present

Currently volunteering at an NGO as a researcher for thier flagship projects: Paperbridge, and Vidya Vistar.

Institute Projects

A learning aid to teach designerly thinking Mar 2021

Created and tested a learning aid that introduces the concept of designerly thinking to students. It incorporates mechanisms to teach students about visual compositions, and helps them to express their decisions as a designer.

A book donation platform service Dec 2020

Designed a platform service for NGO volunteers, to facilitate the movement of donated books, from donors to libraries.

MiDoRe Feb 2019

An assistive wearable for visually impaired, to learn, read, and play sheet music in real time. [Under Digital Fabrication.]

Sensable Jan 2019

Sensable - Experiments with a Real Time Emotion Recognition tool, was a design fiction narrative created as part of the Trends in Interactive Technologies course.

Previous Projects

Virtual Vidyalaya Oct 2015 – Apr 2019

An online educational game / portal by which visually impaired students can attend school virtually. Me and my team built and created an entire MMORPG framework from scratch.